JACOB MARTHALLER

jacob.r.marthaller@gmail.com \& +1.714.809.5895 \Quad \text{\$\text{\$\text{\$O}\$} \text{ Los Angeles Metropolitan Area} github.com/jmarthaller

linkedin.com/in/jacob-marthaller ••• marthaller-jr.medium.com/

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A design-minded developer with a background in legal services and management. Experienced in JavaScript-based programming, especially React and Redux, as well as Ruby on Rails. Committed to consistency and transparency, dedicated to continuous development, and energized by a challenge.

SKILLS

JavaScript • TypeScript • React • Redux • Ruby on Rails • HTML • CSS • SQL • PostgreSQL • SQLite • Git • Node.is • Bootstrap • MongoDB • Docker • Express • GraphQL • Webpack

PROJECTS

Putrid Potatoes (React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL) Social media web app democratizing movie reviews







- Utilized Redux-Toolkit for more opinionated, global state management for CRUD functions
- Communicated with multiple endpoints from The Movie Database's API to obtain data on film and television
- Integrated EmailJS into application to allow users to communicate via email
- Wrote ActiveRecord validations to support a seamless user experience (UX)

PolentaToGoAround (React, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL) Web app to fight food scarcity by connecting users to restaurants LIVE LINK GITHUB

- Ensured a smooth UX through React hooks and React Router for client-side routing.
- Managed application state with React-Redux
- Scraped the Zomato API to acquire restaurant data
- Used SourceTree as a GUI tool to ensure version control best practices

YouTravel (JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap) YouTube inspired site focused exclusively on travel videos

LIVE LINK



- Developed a single page app enabling users to view and post videos based on a selected city and video category. To post a video, users use a YouTube URL which is then parsed and saved on the backend.
- Manipulated the DOM, allowing users to see new videos, likes, and comments in real-time.
- Built multiple RESTful API endpoints using ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL, and Ruby on Rails
- Following deployment on Heroku and Netlify, refactored application using lessons learned from Clean Code and Refactoring

EXPERIENCE

Hearth.io



Software Engineer

March 2021 - Present

Remote

- Refactored home page, profile page using TypeScript to increase codebase readability.
- Leveraged GraphQL to fetch and describe data throughout the application to reduce network requests
- Enhanced the mobile web experience by making the home page mobile responsive
- Worked with DevOps team to set up docker environments for new and legacy applications
- Conducted market research with potential users
- Employed Storybook and Patternfly to streamline UI component development and testing

Neal R. Gross & Co, Inc

Digital Court Reporter/Technical Writer

January 2016 – February 2020

Washington, DC

- Designed a FOIA request-response pipeline to track bids, improving nationwide bidding success rate by 25%
- Recorded and transcribed 300+ criminal and civil legal proceedings
- Drafted policy-driven technical reports for public and private sector clients

Taylored Productions

Chief Operations Officer

January 2012 - August 2013

Tustin, CA

- Launched a commercial video production company and oversaw operations for over two dozen clients
- Implemented accounting procedures that resulted in a budget surplus
- Supervised and trained 5 person team of apprentice video editors on Final Cut X software

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

March 2021

Immersive Full-Stack Web Development Program

University of Virginia

June 2015

MA: Religious Studies

California State University, Fullerton

December 2012

BA: Comparative Religions, magna cum laude

EXTRACURRICULARS

Environment America

November 2015 - Present

Volunteer